<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DPSN Home on Data Protection Scholars Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/</link><description>Recent content in DPSN Home on Data Protection Scholars Network</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>the authors</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dataprotectionscholars.network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 29 January</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffees-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffees-january-2024/</guid><description>The Data Protection Scholars Network (DPSN) and the LSTS VUB would like to invite you to participate in our new joint initiative called Monthly Digital Coffees.
The purpose of these interactive sessions is to discuss the latest data protection judgments from the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) in an informal setting. We will focus on the 1-2 most interesting judgments that have been on the agenda at the Court in the past month.</description></item><item><title>DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress event on Friday 19 January 2024 online (Programme)</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-programme/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-programme/</guid><description>On the 19th of January 2024 the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) organises its third international meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, between 15:00 and 18:00 Brussels time. Format/What to expect Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for concise presentations that the Network launched back in 2023.
Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present their current work in 3 slides and 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Call for participants: the third DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress online event (19 January 2024)</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-new/</guid><description>Call for participants: the third DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress online event (19 January 2024) Would you like to share your research with fellow data protection academics worldwide?
Do it together with the DPSN community!
One of our network’s missions is to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better. The previous International Researchers Online Meet-up events brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars worldwide.</description></item><item><title>Event: Publishing on Data Protection: Monographs and Generalist Journals</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishingevent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishingevent/</guid><description>Dear DPSN community,
We hope you had a nice summer break and are very happy to inform you that we will return with our activities soon!
On September 14th from 13:00 to 14:30 CET, the DPSN is delighted to host an online seminar in which our very own Dr. Orla Lynskey (London School of Economics) and Prof. Lee Andrew Bygrave (University of Oslo) will be talking about publishing on data protection in generalist journals and as monographs.</description></item><item><title>Online lecture by Prof. Christopher Kuner: Publishing in an international law journal: the editor’s perspective</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishing-in-an-international-law-journal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishing-in-an-international-law-journal/</guid><description>On Thursday, 29 June, from 4.30-6.00pm CET, the DPSN is delighted to host an online lecture by Prof. Christopher Kuner on publishing in an international law journal, from his perspective as an editor. Dr. Christopher Kuner has been active in EU and global data protection law since the 1990s as a lawyer, author, and academic. He was previously director of the Brussels Privacy Hub and professor of law at the Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), and has taught at the University of Cambridge, the European University Institute, and the Hague Academy of International Law.</description></item><item><title>The State of Data Protection Law Academia</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-cpdp2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-cpdp2023/</guid><description>On the 25th of May 2023, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) will participate at Computers, Privacy &amp;amp; Data Protection (CPDP) 2023 This will be an in-person event scheduled for May 25th (Thursday) between 17:15 and 18:30 at M-Village Grande.
As you may have noticed, a couple of weeks ago we published a word cloud to solicit the active participation of our entire community and identify the most pressing issues in the academic world of data protection.</description></item><item><title>A Conversation on the Careers Beyond Academia</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/beyond-academia-event/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/beyond-academia-event/</guid><description>On the 9th of May 2023, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) is organising a special discussing on the careers beyond Academia. The event will take place online, between 17:00 and 18:30 Brussels Time. This is a panel discussion consisting of four speakers who, after having obtained their PhDs on information regulation/data protection topics, are now pursuing different careers beyond the Academia:
Dr. Ben Hayes (AWO)
Dr. MacKenzie Common (Oversight Board)</description></item><item><title>DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress event on Friday 27th January 2023 online</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023-registrations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023-registrations/</guid><description>On the 27th of January 2023, coinciding with International Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) organises its second international meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, between 15:00 and 18:00 Brussels time. Format/What to expect Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for very short presentations that the Network launched back in 2022. As we wanted to give a forum to all relevant applicants to present, we decided to make the event an hour longer.</description></item><item><title>Reading Groups and Book Clubs about data protection law and privacy in December 2022 and January 2023</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/bookclubs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/bookclubs/</guid><description>Interested in Reading Groups and Book Clubs about Data Protection and Privacy?
On Monday 19 December 2022, at 12:00-13:00 CET you can join the second Privacy Book Club meeting organized by researchers of the Digital Legal Lab. They will be discussing Privacy is power (2021) by Véliz, C. (Melville House). More information about registration, as well as the Book Club and its next activities can be found here.
On Tuesday 10 January 2023, at 16:00-17:30 CET you can join the online Book Club #9, organized by researchers of the Law, Science, Technology and Society (LSTS) Research Group of the Vrije Universiteit Brussel.</description></item><item><title>Call for participants: the second DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress event will take place on Friday 27th January 2023 online</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023/</guid><description>Would you like to argue about your research? Do it together with the DPSN community!
Call for participants One of our network&amp;rsquo;s missions is to create a platform for people to get to know each other&amp;rsquo;s work better. With this in mind, we are once again calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper, or brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>Launching the DPSN online seminar series</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/seminar-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/seminar-series/</guid><description>This fall we kick start our brand new online seminar series with two exciting seminars:
9th November 16:00 – 17:30 Brussels Time: Conducting DPIAs with Oskar J. Gstrein Data Protection Impact Assessments (DPIAs) are a useful method to spark an interdisciplinary discussion about the collection, storage, management and sharing of personal data. While the GDPR makes them mandatory in certain scenarios of data use, the methodology to implement them varies. In this session we explore ways to teach how to do a DPIA, especially in interdisciplinary teaching settings and scenarios where emerging technologies play a role.</description></item><item><title>DPSN Empirical Study for Access Now: 'The right to lodge a data protection complaint: OK, but then what?'!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn_accessnow_study2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn_accessnow_study2022/</guid><description>The Data Protection Law Scholars Network is glad to present its first research output, a pan-European empirical study on the right to lodge a data protection complaint under the General Data Protection Regulation!
The Report &amp;lsquo;The right to lodge a data protection complaint: OK, but then what?&amp;rsquo; was issued in June 2022.
Authors: Gloria González Fuster (Law,Science, Technology &amp;amp; Society (LSTS), Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB)), Jef Ausloos (Institute for Information Law (IViR), University of Amsterdam (UvA)), Damian Bons (IViR, UvA), Lee A.</description></item><item><title>Visit our DPSN Booth at the EDPS Conference 2022 in Brussels!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-edps-conference-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-edps-conference-2022/</guid><description>The Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) participates with a booth at the 2022 EDPS Conference &amp;ldquo;The Future of Data Protection: Effective Enforcement in the Digital World&amp;rdquo;!
The event takes place on 16 &amp;amp; 17 June 2022 in Brussels. The venue of the EDPS conference is The Egg (Rue Barastraat, 175 1070 Brussels, Belgium) and is open to registered participants. When and where can you find our booth? We will be present both days at the riverside area of The Egg!</description></item><item><title>DPSN Launch at CPDP 2022</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</guid><description>After its first online meet-up in January 2022 on International Data Protection Day that brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) will have its official launch in-person at CPDP2022 on Monday 23 May 2022, 19:00-20:00 BXL time at Maison des Arts (Chau. de Haecht 147, 1030 Schaerbeek)! Drinks and some fingerfood will be provided.
At this event, you can expect to meet our members, including many of its Steering and Management Committee members, and network with fellow data protection scholars in an informal setting, as well as engage in an open discussion about what such a network can do for members in order to facilitate their work in the field of data protection.</description></item><item><title>Data Protection Day Event 2022 - Summary</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organised the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world.
27 speakers, divided into two parallel sessions, presented in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, a collection of educational material, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>Final programme for our online event on the international Data Protection Day!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organises the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, at 13:00-15:10 Brussels time.
Format/What to expect Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for very short presentations that the Network launched back in December 2021. Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.</description></item><item><title>DPSN Event on International Data Protection Day</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</guid><description>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the DPSN will organise the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers.
We want to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better. With this in mind, we are calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper or brand new project.</description></item><item><title>The DPSN at CPDP LatAm 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</guid><description>We are very glad to participate with a panel to the Conference CPDP LatAm 2021 taking place from July 14th to 16th 2021. The panel takes place on July 16th (Room 3), 10:00-11:30 BRT/ 16:00-17:30 CEST. We hope to meet many of you there!
Panel: Data protection law scholars of the world, unite! (in little groups?) Towards a global data protection network?
In light of the growing importance of data protection laws across the world, there is an increased need for robust international expert networks in the field.</description></item><item><title>TILTing 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</guid><description>We are very glad to participate to the Conference TILTing Perspectives 2021: Regulating in Times of Crisis taking place from May 19th to 21st 2021. We thank the organisers for their support in promoting the setting up of this Network, and hope to meet many of you there.</description></item><item><title>About the Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/steering_and_management_committees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/steering_and_management_committees/</guid><description>The daily management of the Data Protection Law Scholars Network is currently led by the following Steering Committee:
Gloria González Fuster, Research Professor, Vrije Universiteit Brussel Jef Ausloos, Postdoctoral Researcher, Universiteit van Amsterdam Kristina Irion, Associate Professor, Universiteit van Amsterdam Eleni Kosta, Professor of Technology Law and Human Rights, Tilburg University Lee A Bygrave, Professor, University of Oslo Franziska Boehm, Professor, Leibniz-Institute for Information Infrastructure in Karlsruhe (FIZ) and the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) Orla Lynskey, Associate Professor, London School of Economics Michael Veale, Lecturer in Digital Rights and Regulation, University College London The Management Committee coordinating the Network is composed of:</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/contact/</guid><description>Sign-up to our newsletter by sending us a subscription email. If you do not receive back an email with instructions for the confirmation of your subscription within few minutes, please check your spam folder. For information, contact us at dpsn@posteo.eu.
If you wish to unsubscribe from our mailing list, simply send an unsubscritption email.</description></item><item><title>Useful DP Links</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/useful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/useful/</guid><description>General European Commission &amp;ndash; Data protection https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en
Council of Europe Data Protection website
Global Privacy Assembly (GPA) https://globalprivacyassembly.org/
European Data Protection Board (EDPB) https://edpb.europa.eu/edpb_en
European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS) https://edps.europa.eu/_en
GDPR Hub https://gdprhub.eu/index.php?title=Welcome_to_GDPRhub
Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Law (CIPIL) overview of national https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/european-data-protection-national-laws-current-and-historic and transnational https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/pan-european-data-protection-and-e-privacy data protection instruments
Computers, Privacy &amp;amp; Data Protection (CPDP) panel videos https://www.youtube.com/c/CPDPConferences/videos?view=0&amp;amp;sort=da&amp;amp;flow=grid
Useful Documents European Court of Human Rights (ECtHR), Factsheet: Personal Data Protection, December 2021 https://www.</description></item></channel></rss>