<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DPSN Home on Data Protection Scholars Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/</link><description>Recent content in DPSN Home on Data Protection Scholars Network</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>the authors</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dataprotectionscholars.network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Call for participants: the fourth DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress online event will take place on January 23rd, 2025 - Deadline Extended to 6 January 2025</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>Would you like to share your research with fellow data protection academics worldwide?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do it together with the DPSN community!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/a18ed8d3-8abb-4e87-a0f5-e1102c50d070" alt="signal-2024-11-19-123021">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="call-for-participants">&lt;strong>Call for participants&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of our network’s missions is to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better.
The previous International Researchers Online Meet-up events was extremely successful. With this in mind,
we are once again calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD,
interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper, or brand-new project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 27 November 2024</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-november-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-november-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in staying up-to-date on the latest judgments of the EU Court of Justice,
do not miss the monthly digital coffee event co-organised by DPSN and LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past
month. This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 25 September 2024</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-september-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-september-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in staying up-to-date on the latest judgments of the EU Court of Justice,
do not miss the monthly digital coffee event co-organised by DPSN and LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past
month. This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join Us at TILTing Perspectives 2024 for an Inspiring Networking Expierence</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/116156905/08e68676-b02c-42b3-afd6-f50c4e661b7b" alt="Tilting_flyer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce that DPSN is hosting the Social Hour Networking Session during TILTing Perspectives 2024.
This event is dedicated to fostering connections and sparking discussions among data protection law enthusiasts and professionals!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="event-highlights">Event Highlights:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>•	&lt;strong>Dates&lt;/strong>: Mark your calendars for July 9th, 2024, from 17:30 to 18:30 CEST during the networking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•	&lt;strong>Networking:&lt;/strong> Engage with peers and find research collaborators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•	&lt;strong>Discussions:&lt;/strong> Delve into data protection topics with our unique conversation prompts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 26 June 2024</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-june-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-june-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in staying up-to-date on the latest judgments of the EU Court of Justice,
do not miss the monthly digital coffee event co-organised by DPSN and LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past
month. This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recap: The Ultimate Data Protection CPDP Quiz at the 2024 CPDP Conference!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/recap-cpdp2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/recap-cpdp2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>DPSN achieved great success at the 2024 Computer, Privacy, and Data Protection Conference (CPDP)
with an innovative and engaging event format: the Ultimate Data Protection CPDP Quiz.
This quiz drew in over 80 participants, leading them on an immersive journey through the world of data protection,
featuring a wide array of over 40 data protection-related questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The event was designed to mimic a TV show, with Romain Robert (EDPS) serving as the charismatic moderator and expert quizmasters Jef Ausloos (IViR)
and Gloria González Fuster (VUB) ensuring that all the rules were meticulously followed.
The top six scorers were then invited to engage in a lively battle of GDPR charades, adding an entertaining and competitive element to the event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 28 May 2024</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-may/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-may/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in staying up-to-date on the latest judgments of the EU Court of Justice,
do not miss the monthly digital coffee event co-organised by DPSN and LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past
month. This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) at the Computers, Privacy and Data Protection Conference (CPDP) on Wednesday, 22 May 2024</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/116156905/f9337e64-7557-476f-b9c5-db669cd475ac" alt="THE ULTIMATE CPDPUB QUIZ(5)">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We invite all CPDP participants to join us for “The Ultimate Data Protection CPDPub Quiz”.
This fun event takes you on an exciting journey through the world of data protection, presented in a lively and interactive format.
The quiz will be led by expert quizmasters and esteemed jury members, and you will have the chance to showcase your knowledge by answering stimulating and thought-provoking questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The quiz topics will range from entertainment and sports to geography, arts, literature, and history.
All you need to participate is your phone and your data protection knowledge.
You will compete with other participants in a friendly yet spirited atmosphere, and the top six scorers will advance to The Final.
In the final, they will be paired in random matches for a chance to win the prestigious title of “the CPDPub Quiz Champion”.
The ultimate champion will receive a surprise prize and esteemed international recognition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 30 April 2024</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-april/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-april/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in staying up-to-date on the latest judgments of the EU Court of Justice,
do not miss the monthly digital coffee event co-organised by DPSN and LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past
month. This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 26 March</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-march/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffee-march/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you interested in staying up to date with the latest data protection judgments from the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU)?
If so, we have some exciting news for you! We are thrilled to announce our new initiative, Monthly Digital Coffee, in collaboration with LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past month.
This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 27 February</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffees-february-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffees-february-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you interested in staying up to date with the latest data protection judgments from the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU)?
If so, we have some exciting news for you! We are thrilled to announce our new initiative, Monthly Digital Coffee, in collaboration with LSTS VUB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us for an informal exchange of ideas and insights as we discuss the most interesting 1-2 judgments on the agenda at the CJEU in the past month.
This is an excellent opportunity to stay informed about the latest developments in data protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join DPSN and LSTS for Monthly Digital Coffees: Latest Data Protection Judgments from CJEU on 29 January</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffees-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/monthly-digital-coffees-january-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Protection Scholars Network (DPSN) and the LSTS VUB would like to invite you to participate in our new joint initiative called Monthly Digital Coffees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purpose of these interactive sessions is to discuss the latest data protection judgments from the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) in an informal setting.
We will focus on the 1-2 most interesting judgments that have been on the agenda at the Court in the past month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress event on Friday 19 January 2024 online (Programme)</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-programme/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-programme/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="on-the-19th-of-january-2024-the-data-protection-law-scholars-network-dpsn-organises-its-third-international-meet-up-of-data-protection-law-researchers-the-event-will-take-place-online-between-1500-and-1800-brussels-time">&lt;strong>On the 19th of January 2024 the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) organises its third international meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, between 15:00 and 18:00 Brussels time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/116156905/6b6b42a8-bfbf-42a7-bad0-6283abe76dfc" alt="DPSN Annual Event Poster">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="formatwhat-to-expect">Format/What to expect&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for concise presentations that the Network launched back in 2023.&lt;br>
Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present their current work in 3 slides and 5 minutes. The programme encompasses 3 sessions.
Throughout the event, participants will be actively encouraged to engage with each other&amp;rsquo;s work and network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Call for participants: the third DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress online event (19 January 2024)</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2024-new/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="call-for-participants-the-third-dpsn-international-data-protection-day-work-in-progress-online-event-19-january-2024">&lt;strong>Call for participants: the third DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress online event (19 January 2024)&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Would you like to share your research with fellow data protection academics worldwide?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do it together with the DPSN community!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/116156905/6b6b42a8-bfbf-42a7-bad0-6283abe76dfc" alt="DPSN Annual Event Poster">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of our network’s missions is to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better. The previous International Researchers Online Meet-up events brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars worldwide.
We are once again calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper, or brand-new project. All levels of seniority are welcome, the only requirement being the willingness to engage with others in rigorous yet friendly spirits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Event: Publishing on Data Protection: Monographs and Generalist Journals</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishingevent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishingevent/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/85340119/95e342cc-a19a-4683-986f-48ca247a66e1" alt="September 14th Seminar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dear DPSN community,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hope you had a nice summer break and are very happy to inform you that we will return with our activities soon!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On &lt;strong>September 14th from 13:00 to 14:30 CET&lt;/strong>, the DPSN is delighted to host an online seminar in which our very own Dr. Orla Lynskey (London School of Economics) and Prof. Lee Andrew Bygrave (University of Oslo) will be talking about publishing on data protection in generalist journals and as monographs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Online lecture by Prof. Christopher Kuner: Publishing in an international law journal: the editor’s perspective</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishing-in-an-international-law-journal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/publishing-in-an-international-law-journal/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="on-thursday-29-june-from-430-600pm-cet--the-dpsn-is-delighted-to-host-an-online-lecture-by-prof-christopher-kuner-on-publishing-in-an-international-law-journal-from-his-perspective-as-an-editor">&lt;strong>On Thursday, 29 June, from 4.30-6.00pm CET, the DPSN is delighted to host an online lecture by Prof. Christopher Kuner on publishing in an international law journal, from his perspective as an editor.&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/116156905/af3ee140-70db-4574-9473-51eb26abcf0c" alt="Kuner - online seminar series(1)">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dr. Christopher Kuner has been active in EU and global data protection law since the 1990s as a lawyer, author, and academic. He was previously director of the Brussels Privacy Hub and professor of law at the Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), and has taught at the University of Cambridge, the European University Institute, and the Hague Academy of International Law. He is currently Affiliate Professor at the University of Copenhagen, a Visiting Fellow at Maastricht University, and Senior Privacy Counsel in the Brussels office of Wilson Sonsini, as well as being a member of the European Commission&amp;rsquo;s Multisectoral Stakeholder Group on the GDPR. The author of numerous articles and books, Dr. Kuner is founder and editor-in-chief of the law journal International Data Privacy Law and one of the principal editors of the commentary on the GDPR published by Oxford University Press, as well as editor of the OUP monograph series on privacy and data protection law.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Brussels effect in China: What happened after the Personal Information Protection Law (PIPL) and how will it go?</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/brussels-effect-in-china-event/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/brussels-effect-in-china-event/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="on-wednesday-21-june-from-1300-to-1500-cest-dpsn-together-with-lsts---vub-are-organising-an-online-seminar-themed-the-brussels-effect-in-china-what-happened-after-the-personal-information-protection-law-pipl-and-how-will-it-go">&lt;strong>On Wednesday, 21 June, from 13:00 to 15:00 CEST, DPSN together with LSTS - VUB are organising an online seminar themed ‘The Brussels effect in China: What happened after the Personal Information Protection Law (PIPL) and how will it go?’&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;img width="452" alt="image" src="https://github.com/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork/dataprotectionscholarsnetwork.github.io/assets/116156905/d0f062bd-cf32-4900-8403-3c3a7c5be5ff">
&lt;p>The Brussels effect has become a buzzword with the development of global data protection standards in recent years. The Personal Information Protection Law (PIPL),
China&amp;rsquo;s counterpart to the GDPR, was also created under the EU’s regulatory gravity. After one and a half years of enforcement of the PIPL,
questions have risen as to how well the imported regulatory tools have settled into China’s reality and how it has impacted the digital industry and individuals both domestic and global.
Against the backdrop of the growing call for reform of the EU data protection law, how will China react to similar regulatory challenges such as the ineffectiveness of informed consent and the influence of the powerful internet giants?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The State of Data Protection Law Academia</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-cpdp2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-cpdp2023/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="on-the-25th-of-may-2023-the-data-protection-law-scholars-network-dpsn-will-participate-at-computers-privacy--data-protection-cpdp-2023">&lt;strong>On the 25th of May 2023, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) will participate at Computers, Privacy &amp;amp; Data Protection (CPDP) 2023&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This will be an in-person event scheduled for May 25th (Thursday) between 17:15 and 18:30 at M-Village Grande.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you may have noticed, a couple of weeks ago we published a word cloud to solicit the active participation of our entire community and identify the most pressing issues in the academic world of data protection. Specifically, we classified them as follows:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Conversation on the Careers Beyond Academia</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/beyond-academia-event/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/beyond-academia-event/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="on-the-9th-of-may-2023-the-data-protection-law-scholars-network-dpsn-is-organising-a-special-discussing-on-the-careers-beyond-academia-the-event-will-take-place-online-between-1700-and-1830-brussels-time">&lt;strong>On the 9th of May 2023, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) is organising a special discussing on the careers beyond Academia. The event will take place online, between 17:00 and 18:30 Brussels Time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/116156905/234305621-16f8f5de-d7bb-4c88-acd0-139c5b7a1878.png" alt="DPSN Careers Outside Academia Event">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a panel discussion consisting of four speakers who, after having obtained their PhDs on information regulation/data protection topics, are now pursuing different careers beyond the Academia:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dr. Ben Hayes (AWO)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress event on Friday 27th January 2023 online</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023-registrations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023-registrations/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="on-the-27th-of-january-2023-coinciding-with-international-data-protection-day-the-data-protection-law-scholars-network-dpsn-organises-its-second-international-meet-up-of-data-protection-law-researchers-the-event-will-take-place-online-between-1500-and-1800-brussels-time">&lt;strong>On the 27th of January 2023, coinciding with International Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) organises its second international meet-up of data protection law researchers. The event will take place online, between 15:00 and 18:00 Brussels time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/85340119/212054140-426d2fbb-a5ae-4678-b108-c31f6695a270.png" alt="DP Day event - registrants">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="formatwhat-to-expect">Format/What to expect&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for very short presentations that the Network launched back in 2022. As we wanted to give a forum to all relevant applicants to present, we decided to make the event an hour longer.&lt;br>
Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work. The programme encompasses 2 sessions which consist of two parallel streams each with an equal number of speakers. The 3rd and final session takes place in plenary. The streams are loosely thematically organised while still covering a diverse and innovative range of topics in data protection law. The programme has a further element of surprise, meaning that we will not announce the names of the speakers per session, but &lt;strong>attendees will be allocated randomly either to Parallel Stream 1 or to Parallel Stream 2.&lt;/strong> Throughout the event, participants will be actively encouraged to engage with each other&amp;rsquo;s work and network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reading Groups and Book Clubs about data protection law and privacy in December 2022 and January 2023</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/bookclubs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/bookclubs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interested in Reading Groups and Book Clubs about Data Protection and Privacy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On &lt;strong>Monday 19 December 2022, at 12:00-13:00 CET&lt;/strong> you can join the &lt;a href="https://www.sectorplandls.nl/wordpress/privacy-book-club/">second Privacy Book Club meeting&lt;/a> organized by researchers of the &lt;a href="https://www.sectorplandls.nl/wordpress/">Digital Legal Lab&lt;/a>.
They will be discussing Privacy is power (2021) by Véliz, C. (Melville House). More information about registration, as well as the Book Club and its next
activities can be found &lt;a href="https://www.sectorplandls.nl/wordpress/privacy-book-club/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On &lt;strong>Tuesday 10 January 2023, at 16:00-17:30 CET&lt;/strong> you can join &lt;a href="https://lsts.research.vub.be/en/20220920">the online Book Club #9&lt;/a>, organized by researchers of &lt;a href="https://lsts.research.vub.be/en">the Law, Science, Technology and
Society (LSTS) Research Group&lt;/a> of the Vrije Universiteit Brussel. This time they will be discussing a book picked from &lt;a href="https://lsts.research.vub.be/en/LSTS_list_2021">the LSTS Books of the Year 2021 list&lt;/a>: Invisible women - Data Bias in a World Designed for Men (2019) by Criado Perez, C. . Lina Jasmontaite will open the discussion with a brief
prologue on the book. More information about registration, as well as the Book Club and its activities can be found &lt;a href="https://lsts.research.vub.be/en/20220920">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Call for participants: the second DPSN International Data Protection Day work-in-progress event will take place on Friday 27th January 2023 online</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpd2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Would you like to argue about your research? Do it together with the DPSN community!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/116156905/200795314-cec98b0f-ffa5-4d98-ab2e-bc73015df485.png" alt="Call for Participants: International Researchers Online Meet-up">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="call-for-participants">Call for participants&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of our network&amp;rsquo;s missions is to create a platform for people to get to know each other&amp;rsquo;s work better. With this in mind, we are once again calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper, or brand-new project. All levels of seniority are welcome, the only requirement being to be open to listen to others in a rigorous yet friendly spirit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Launching the DPSN online seminar series</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/seminar-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/seminar-series/</guid><description>&lt;p>This fall we kick start our brand new online seminar series with two exciting seminars:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/85340119/197510578-24dc4760-a697-41ee-ab03-21c3211bbbbb.png" alt="Online seminar series 2022 10 19">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="9th-november-1600--1730-brussels-time-conducting-dpias-with-oskar-j-gstrein">9th November 16:00 – 17:30 Brussels Time: Conducting DPIAs with Oskar J. Gstrein&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Data Protection Impact Assessments (DPIAs) are a useful method to spark an interdisciplinary discussion about the collection, storage, management and sharing of personal data. While the GDPR makes them mandatory in certain scenarios of data use, the methodology to implement them varies. In this session we explore ways to teach how to do a DPIA, especially in interdisciplinary teaching settings and scenarios where emerging technologies play a role. The material presented in this session is based on the COMENIUS project Privacy in Research, which was developed by Esther Hoorn at the University of Groningen in The Netherlands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DPSN Empirical Study for Access Now: 'The right to lodge a data protection complaint: OK, but then what?'!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn_accessnow_study2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn_accessnow_study2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Data Protection Law Scholars Network is glad to present its first research output, &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2022/07/GDPR-Complaint-study.pdf">a pan-European empirical study
on the right to lodge a data protection complaint under the General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Report &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2022/07/GDPR-Complaint-study.pdf">&amp;lsquo;The right to lodge a data protection complaint: OK, but then what?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> was issued in June 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Authors: Gloria González Fuster (Law,Science, Technology &amp;amp; Society (LSTS), Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB)),
Jef Ausloos (Institute for Information Law (IViR), University of Amsterdam (UvA)), Damian Bons (IViR, UvA),
Lee A. Bygrave (Norwegian Research Centre for Computers and Law, University of Oslo), Barbara da Rosa
Lazarotto (LSTS, VUB), Laura Drechsler (FWO / LSTS, VUB), Olga Gkotsopoulou (LSTS, VUB), Christopher Hristov (IViR, UvA),
Kristina Irion (IViR, UvA), Lina Jasmontaite (LSTS, VUB), Charlotte Kroese (IViR, UvA), Orla Lynskey (LSE Law School,
Maria Magierska (European University Institute (EUI)).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visit our DPSN Booth at the EDPS Conference 2022 in Brussels!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-edps-conference-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/dpsn-at-edps-conference-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) participates with a booth at the 2022 EDPS Conference &amp;ldquo;The Future of Data Protection: Effective Enforcement in the Digital World&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The event takes place on 16 &amp;amp; 17 June 2022 in Brussels. The venue of the EDPS conference is The Egg (Rue Barastraat, 175 1070 Brussels, Belgium) and is open to registered participants.
When and where can you find our booth? We will be present both days at the riverside area of The Egg! We will have flyers and limited edition stickers for you! Do not miss the opportunity to get to know our work and have your say about the network&amp;rsquo;s next steps.
You will also have the chance to meet many members of our steering and management committees who are speaking, moderating or attending.
We are looking forward to meet you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DPSN Launch at CPDP 2022</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>After &lt;a href="https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/">its first online meet-up in January 2022 on International Data Protection Day&lt;/a> that brought together more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network (DPSN) will have &lt;a href="https://www.cpdpconferences.org/events/dpsn-launch-at-cpdp2022">its official launch in-person at CPDP2022&lt;/a> on Monday 23 May 2022, 19:00-20:00 BXL time at Maison des Arts (Chau. de Haecht 147, 1030 Schaerbeek)! Drinks and some fingerfood will be provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>At this event, you can expect to meet our members, including many of its Steering and Management Committee members, and network with fellow data
protection scholars in an informal setting, as well as engage in an open discussion about what such a network can do for members in order to facilitate
their work in the field of data protection.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Protection Day Event 2022 - Summary</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/data-protection-day-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organised &lt;strong>the first ever international
quick meet-up of data protection law researchers&lt;/strong>. The event brought together &lt;strong>more than 150 data protection law scholars from all over the world&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>27 speakers, divided into two parallel sessions, presented in 3 slides and 5 minutes their current work&lt;/strong>, be it a developing PhD, an interesting
master thesis, a collection of educational material, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project. &lt;strong>Attendees were randomly allocated to one
of the two parallel streams, without knowing which speakers they will be listening to&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Final programme for our online event on the international Data Protection Day!</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event28012022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the Data Protection Law Scholars Network organises &lt;strong>the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers&lt;/strong>.
The event will take place online, at 13:00-15:10 Brussels time&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="formatwhat-to-expect">Format/What to expect&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Speakers were selected through a call for abstracts for very short presentations that the Network launched back in December 2021.
&lt;strong>Data protection law scholars of all levels of seniority will present &lt;em>in 3 slides and 5 minutes&lt;/em> their current work&lt;/strong>, be it a developing PhD, an interesting master thesis, an upcoming promising paper or a brand-new project.
The programme encompasses &lt;strong>two sessions, each one consisting of two parallel streams&lt;/strong> with an equal number of speakers.&lt;br>
The streams are not thematically organised but rather cover diverse and innovative topics of data protection law.&lt;br>
The programme has a further element of surprise, meaning that we will not announce the names of the speakers per session, but &lt;strong>attendees will be allocated randomly either to Parallel Stream 1 or to Parallel Stream 2&lt;/strong>.
Throughout the event, participants will be actively encouraged to communicate with each other and network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DPSN Event on International Data Protection Day</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/event_on_int_dp_day/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 28 January 2022, coinciding with the international Data Protection Day, the DPSN will organise the first ever international quick meet-up of data protection law researchers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We want to create a platform for people to get to know each other’s work better. With this in mind, we are calling for expressions of interest to do very short presentations of your research – be it your developing PhD, interesting master thesis, upcoming promising paper or brand new project. All levels of seniority are welcome, the only requirement being to be open to listen to others in a rigorous yet friendly spirit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The DPSN at CPDP LatAm 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/cpdp_latam_panel2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are very glad to participate with a panel to the Conference &lt;a href="https://cpdp.lat/en/program/">CPDP LatAm 2021&lt;/a> taking place from July 14th to 16th 2021. The panel takes place on &lt;strong>July 16th (Room 3), 10:00-11:30 BRT/ 16:00-17:30 CEST&lt;/strong>. We hope to meet many of you there!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Panel: Data protection law scholars of the world, unite! (in little groups?) Towards a global data protection network?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In light of the growing importance of data protection laws across the world, there is an increased need for robust international expert networks in the field. Data protection authorities have been meeting regularly for decades already, in a variety of regional and global events (cf. the ICDPPC, now the Global Privacy Assembly), and there is also a significant rise in networks of privacy professional, synchronizing in numerous and dynamic structures (e.g. IAPP). To our knowledge, however, there are no real equivalent networks in the academic community, at least on the same scale. Indeed, despite some notable exceptions such as the Asian Privacy Scholars Network (APSN), there exist no international networks of scholars devoted to furthering research and education on data protection law. Thus, scholars working in the field lack equivalent networks through which to exchange information, be in contact with each other, and reach to and support newcomers. Can this be changed? Taking as a starting point the launch of the Data Protection Scholars Network, in Europe, this panel aims at discussing:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TILTing 2021</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/post/tilting2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are very glad to participate to the Conference &lt;a href="https://www.tilburguniversity.edu/research/institutes-and-research-groups/tilt/events/tilting-perspectives">TILTing Perspectives 2021: Regulating in Times of Crisis&lt;/a> taking place from May 19th to 21st 2021. We thank the organisers for their support in promoting the setting up of this Network, and hope to meet many of you there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/subscription/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/subscription/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html>
&lt;html lang="en">
&lt;head>
 &lt;meta charset="UTF-8">
 &lt;meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0">
 &lt;style type="text/css">
 #subscription-form {
 background-color: lightsteelblue;
 width: 500px;
 padding: 50px;
 border-radius: 5px;
 }

 #pw-in {
 display: flex;
 flex-direction: column;
 row-gap: 10px;

 }

 form {
 
 display: flex;
 flex-wrap: wrap;
 flex-direction: column;
 
 }

 &lt;/style>
 &lt;title>Document&lt;/title>
&lt;/head>
&lt;body>

 &lt;main>

 &lt;div id="subscription-form">

 &lt;h2>Join the DPSN mailing list&lt;/h2>

 &lt;form method="post" action="https://lists.uvt.nl/mailman/subscribe/data-protection-scholars">
 Your E-mail address: &lt;input name="email"> Your Name (optional):
 &lt;input name="fullname">

 &lt;p>You may enter a privacy password below. This provides only
 mild security, but should prevent others from messing with your
 subscription. &lt;strong>Do not use a valuable password&lt;/strong> as
 it will occasionally be emailed back to you in cleartext. If you
 choose not to enter a password, one will be automatically
 generated for you, and it will be sent to you once you've
 confirmed your subscription. You can always request a mail-back
 of your password when you edit your personal options.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About the Network</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/steering_and_management_committees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/steering_and_management_committees/</guid><description>&lt;p>The daily management of the Data Protection Law Scholars Network is currently led by the following Steering Committee:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://glgonzalezfuster.blog/">Gloria González Fuster&lt;/a>, Research Professor, Vrije Universiteit Brussel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/profiel/a/u/j.ausloos/j.ausloos.html">Jef Ausloos&lt;/a>, Assistant Professor, Universiteit van Amsterdam&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/i/r/k.irion/k.irion.html">Kristina Irion&lt;/a>, Associate Professor, Universiteit van Amsterdam&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.tilburguniversity.edu/staff/e-kosta">Eleni Kosta&lt;/a>, Professor of Technology Law and Human Rights, Tilburg University&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.jus.uio.no/ifp/english/people/aca/lee/">Lee A Bygrave&lt;/a>, Professor, University of Oslo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.fiz-karlsruhe.de/en/bereiche/publikationen-prof-dr-franziska-boehm">Franziska Boehm&lt;/a>, Professor, Leibniz-Institute for Information Infrastructure in Karlsruhe (FIZ) and the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.coleurope.eu/whoswho/person/orla.lynskey">Orla Lynskey&lt;/a>, Professor of Law and Technology, University College London&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://michae.lv">Michael Veale&lt;/a>, Associate Professor in Digital Rights and Regulation, University College London&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Management Committee coordinating the Network is composed of:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sign-up to our newsletter by sending us &lt;a href="mailto:data-protection-scholars-join@lists.uvt.nl?subject=subscribe&amp;amp;body=subscribe">a subscription email&lt;/a>. If you do not receive back an email with instructions for the confirmation of your subscription within few minutes, please check your spam folder. For information, contact us at &lt;a href="mailto:dpscholars@protonmail.com">dpscholars@protonmail.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Useful DP Links</title><link>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/useful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dataprotectionscholars.network/useful/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="general">General&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>European Commission &amp;ndash; Data protection
&lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en">https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.coe.int/en/web/data-protection">Council of Europe Data Protection website&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Global Privacy Assembly (GPA) &lt;a href="https://globalprivacyassembly.org/">https://globalprivacyassembly.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>European Data Protection Board (EDPB)
&lt;a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/edpb_en">https://edpb.europa.eu/edpb_en&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS)
&lt;a href="https://edps.europa.eu/_en">https://edps.europa.eu/_en&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>GDPR Hub &lt;a href="https://gdprhub.eu/index.php?title=Welcome_to_GDPRhub">https://gdprhub.eu/index.php?title=Welcome_to_GDPRhub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Law (CIPIL)
overview of national
&lt;a href="https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/european-data-protection-national-laws-current-and-historic">https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/european-data-protection-national-laws-current-and-historic&lt;/a>
and transnational
&lt;a href="https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/pan-european-data-protection-and-e-privacy">https://www.cipil.law.cam.ac.uk/resources/pan-european-data-protection-and-e-privacy&lt;/a>
data protection instruments&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Computers, Privacy &amp;amp; Data Protection (CPDP) panel videos
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/CPDPConferences/videos?view=0&amp;amp;sort=da&amp;amp;flow=grid">https://www.youtube.com/c/CPDPConferences/videos?view=0&amp;sort=da&amp;flow=grid&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="useful-documents">Useful Documents&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>European Court of Human Rights (ECtHR), &lt;em>Factsheet: Personal Data Protection,&lt;/em> December 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.echr.coe.int/Documents/FS_Data_ENG.pdf">https://www.echr.coe.int/Documents/FS_Data_ENG.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>European Court of Human Rights (ECtHR), &lt;em>Guide to the Case-Law of
the of the European Court of Human Rights on Data Protection,&lt;/em>
December 2020
&lt;a href="https://rm.coe.int/guide-data-protection-eng-1-2789-7576-0899-v-1/1680a20af0">https://rm.coe.int/guide-data-protection-eng-1-2789-7576-0899-v-1/1680a20af0&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>